Ben Wuebker

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Ben.Wuebker@gmail.com | 952-923-6485 | Minneapolis, MN www.linkedin.com/in/bwuebker | www.benwuebker.dev | www.github.com/BenWueb

OBJECTIVE

I am a highly motivated full stack developer based out of Minneapolis, Minnesota. I love creating digital experiences that are both beautiful and functional. Over the years, I've honed my skills in React, Web Design, JavaScript, and many other languages and frameworks to bring my ideas to life. I am seeking a long-term position with an organization that promotes personal development and opportunities for professional growth while utilizing my 10+ years of soft skills and business administration.

SKILLS & ABILITIES

- React
- Javascript
- HTML
- CSS
- NodeJS

- Google Firebase
- TailwindCSS
- MongoDB
- AWS
- GraphQL

- Figma
- Redux
- JWT
- Search Engine Optimization
- MySQL

SOFT SKILLS / PROJECT MANAGEMENT

- A decade of experience in customer service, inside support and Project Management
- Experience hiring, training and managing personnel
- Creating and implementing SOP for new software implementation
- Managing 5-10 large cleanroom construction projects at any given time.

PROJECTS

Social Recipe Application

App | Repo

Description

- React application where you can add, edit, delete, like, comment and share recipes.
- Email authentication and OAuth for account creation.
- Optimized for all devices and viewports.
- This application was built using React.js and Google Firebase.
- The initial dataset was a trove of old recipes passed down from my family that lived on an ancient piece of recipe software. They were extracted and converted into .pdf and .doc files a few years back by a relative. I scraped and wrote a node script to upload to the database.

Support Ticket Application

Repo App

Description

A basic support ticket app built using React, Redux, MongoDB, Express, Axios and JWT. I wanted to build something simple that showcased a variety of skill sets and tools implemented in an organized way following best practices.

Static Sites Highlighting Design Personal Brand Wedding Planner

Site | Repo | Site | Repo

Description

A couple static websites 100% designed and built by me. Built using React and styled components with some subtle animations for a modern and responsive feel.

All sites are optimized for:

- Speed using techniques such as code splitting, optimal image size and format, pagination, lazy loading and utilizing Lighthouse
- SEO using meta tags, correct html tags, Google search console, accessibility best practices and sitemaps

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Remote Solanart 2021-2023

Web Design/Technical Support/Sales & Marketing 2021-2023

- Designed landing pages in Figma
- Formed strategic partnerships with other web3 companies
- Assisted customers with technical support
- Researched, reached out to and pitched potential clients our services

Eden Prairie, MN Production Automation Corp 2013-2021

Project Management/Lead Customer Service Agent/Sales

- Launching, building and maintaining Amazon business account
- Hiring and training customer service personnel and managing the CS department
- Training new employees in SOP, product, software and client relations
- Overseeing all aspects of Ecommerce business
- Managing 5-10 large cleanroom construction projects at any given time. Including moving and purchasing of material, coordinating installs as well as tracking and facilitating all financial aspects of the projects
- Providing specialized support to the companies largest B2B accounts. Ensuring product availability, compliance and on-time delivery
- Troubleshooting technical issues and performing hardware maintenance
- Learning, training and achieving ISO Certification
- Building the customer service department, including creating SOP for maintaining and facilitating ecommerce business

EDUCATION

CompTIA A+ Certified

